<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: conferences | Cristian Planas]]></title>
  <link href="http://Gawyn.github.com/blog/categories/conferences/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://Gawyn.github.com/blog/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-14T20:26:57+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://Gawyn.github.com/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Cristian Planas]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[me@cristianplanas.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Programmer Anarchy]]></title>
    <link href="http://Gawyn.github.com/blog/2012/02/05/programmer-anarchy/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-05T13:10:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://Gawyn.github.com/blog/2012/02/05/programmer-anarchy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the <a href="http://rupy.eu/">Rupy 2011</a>, I assisted to some very interesting
conferences, like the ones by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/josevalim">José Valim</a> or <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/wycats">Yehuda Katz</a>.
 But the conference I remember the most is, by far, Programmer Anarchy.</p>

<p>In it, <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/fgeorge52">Fred George</a> exposes with a great amount of humor a development
process where programmers are not just developing the application, but
designing and modifying it beyond the customer's expectations. He
also reasons the need of removing certain roles (most of them, actually)
that don't produce code in the development process. As the popular agile (or antiagile?) manifesto says...
<a href="http://programming-motherfucker.com/">Programming, Motherfucker!</a></p>

<p>Personally, I have always thought that developers should take a more
active role when discussing the application with the customer: how many
times have we ended coding some feature that we knew for sure that was
stupid? We have to remember that, in the end, we are fucking technology
experts, specially compared to most of the clients (yeah, not being too
humble now). We should be stakeholders, and not minor ones, of our own
projects.</p>

<p>Here you can watch the conference. I would recommend it, even if you are
not very interested in the topic. If you know the IT world, it's really
hilarous:</p>

<iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/32447325?title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0" width="400" height="225" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p><a href="http://vimeo.com/32447325">Fred George - Programmer Anarchy</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/forwardtechnology">Forward Technology</a> on <a href="http://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
