<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: personal | The blog of a developer]]></title>
  <link href="http://Gawyn.github.com/blog/categories/personal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://Gawyn.github.com/blog/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-11T00:53:54+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://Gawyn.github.com/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Cristian Planas]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[me@cristianplanas.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to my new blog!]]></title>
    <link href="http://Gawyn.github.com/blog/2012/01/29/welcome-to-my-new-blog/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-29T03:44:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://Gawyn.github.com/blog/2012/01/29/welcome-to-my-new-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Being at the same time an IT guy and a literature lover, I guess it's normal I created a lot of blogs in my life: <a href="http://gawyn.blogspot.com/">El blog de Gawyn</a>, <a href="http://librosyfilms.wordpress.com/">Libros y Films</a>, and specially <a href="http://cafemarat.blogspot.com/">Café Marat</a> a blog with 73 (long) entries written in almost two years and that even after not being updated for more then three years, is still receiving almost 1.000 visits every month. I also created a cinema magazine, <a href="http://fundidoanegro.net">Fundido a Negro</a> that was also my first experience with Rails.</p>

<p>But, so far, this blogs were essencially about some of my other passions: literature and cinema. <strong>This blog will be different: it's main topic will be my experiences with Ruby and other languages.</strong> Of course, I know that it's always risky to predict the real content of something before creating it, but at least that is my purpose.</p>

<p>But why should a developer write about his job? First of all, to share the new lessons one takes everyday with other developers; right now, for any of us, it's impossible to think about how it would be our coding without the help of the community via Google, blogs or <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/">Stackoverflow</a>. But also because, quoting Einstein:</p>

<blockquote><p>If you can't explain it simply, you don't understand it well enough.</p></blockquote>

<p>And that's enough for this entry. Let the real action begin!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
