<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: tweetmovies | Cristian Planas]]></title>
  <link href="http://Gawyn.github.com/blog/categories/tweetmovies/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://Gawyn.github.com/blog/"/>
  <updated>2012-02-09T15:23:24+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://Gawyn.github.com/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Cristian Planas]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[me@cristianplanas.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Presenting TweetMovies]]></title>
    <link href="http://Gawyn.github.com/blog/2012/02/08/presenting-tweetmovies/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-08T22:37:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://Gawyn.github.com/blog/2012/02/08/presenting-tweetmovies</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When the Web is your passion, you don't have enough with your job:
you continue developing your own tools or applications after hours. Web
developers like to have their own
projects, creations they can feel they own. That's exactly my case.</p>

<p>One of those apps, probably my favorite, is
<a href="http://tweetmovies.net">TweetMovies</a>: a
special social network to discover great films and sharing your
opinion about any of your favorite, or least favorite, movies. <strong>"Tweet.
Read. Share. Discover cinema the social way!"</strong> is the motto of
<a href="http://tweetmovies.net">TweetMovies</a>, and everything in the application, from the specification
to the graphic design, is around that. In the end, we
live in the 2.0 world!</p>

<p><a href="http://tweetmovies.net"><img class="center" src="http://tweetmovies.net/assets/logowithname-7457ed893c957bdf29e70a659a59e3ac.png" title="TweetMovies" alt="The logo of TweetMovies"></a></p>

<p>In the creation of <a href="http://tweetmovies.net">TweetMovies</a>, integration with other social networks
was truly important: users don't need to register in TwM, as they can
access the main features of the application only logging in with your
Twitter account. <a href="http://tweetmovies.net">TweetMovies</a> also integrates with Facebook as any
comment written on our application can be redirected to the Twitter and FB
accounts of the users, giving you the power to share your views on
movies with your friends and the world.</p>

<p>One of the main goals of <a href="http://tweetmovies.net">TweetMovies</a> was to create a space where all the
opinions around the film world could be organized. Twitter and the other
social networks are fantastic jungles of information, an utopy for
any datamining lover. But often it's hard to find interesting and
fair judgments about some topics: TwM tries to be a solution to that. The
opinions of our users are ranked by other users and our own algorithm,
giving them the chance to read first the most important ones. This way,
TwM tries to be not only a social tool, but also a point of reference
for anyone interested in movies. With
<a href="http://tweetmovies.net">TweetMovies</a>, you will get a quick
and attractive answer to the most typical questions: Should I watch
this movie? Is it good? <strong>In TweetMovies we don't believe that a number is
enough, like other applications do. For us, words are more important than
numbers: anyone trusts more a friend giving a reasonable opinion than other saying 'six point three'.</strong></p>

<p>Being a complex and modern application, in the creation of
<a href="http://tweetmovies.net">TweetMovies</a>
were used a great variety of tools. As a true Ruby believer, I used
Rails in the application development. For the integration with FB and
Twitter, Omniauth; for user authentication, Devise; and in the general
design of the site, Slim, Sass, CoffeeScript and JQuery. Lots of other
tools, mainly ruby gems, were used but it would be boring to talk about
all of them.</p>

<p>That's all. I hope you try and enjoy
<a href="http://tweetmovies.net">TweetMovies</a>. Because as Truffaut
said, <em>Le Cinema Règne!</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
